Guide to the Lawrence M. Noble, Associate Secretary, Yale University, Records Concerning the Athletic Association
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Lawrence M. Noble, associate secretary, Yale University, records concerning the Athletic Association
1972-1977
RU 67
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
The records consist of correspondence, complaints, budget materials, and administrative records documenting committees, coaches, sports, personnel, intercollegiate athletics, investments, real estate, facilities, and legislation concerning athletics at Yale.
Yale University. Office of the Secretary
Noble, Lawrence M.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-B (YRG 4-B), Records of Yale deputy, associate, and assistant secretaries.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Office of the Secretary, 1982.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, complaints, budget materials, and administrative records documenting committees, coaches, sports, personnel, intercollegiate athletics, investments, real estate, facilities, and legislation concerning athletics at Yale.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to Boxes 2 and 6 are restricted. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Athletics; College sports; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University. Office of the Secretary; Yale University Athletic Association; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Sports
- Records of Lawrence M. Noble concerning the Athletic Association, 1972-1977; Accession 1983-A-034
  - Administration (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admissions (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action Plan (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alterations (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Basketball (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board of Governors Prior Years (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board Meetings, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board Meetings Prior Years (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Budget, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9 - 10)
  - Business Manager (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Captains (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Coaches (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Commission on Athletics (Box 2, Folder 14 - 16)
  - Commission on Athletics: Financial (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Community Relations (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Complaints (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Corporation Subcommittee on Athletics (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until January 1, 2027
  - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Crew (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Cullman Courts (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Employment Contracts (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Director of Athletics (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Football Attendance (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Facilities (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Football (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Gym (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Gymnastics (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Hockey (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Hockey Coach (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Intercollegiate Athletics at Yale (report on) (Box 3, Folder 34 - 35)
  - Intercollegiate Athletics - Background material (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Ivy League (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Ivy League Complaints (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Lacrosse (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - National Collegiate Athletics Association (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Outdoor Education Center (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Paddle Tennis Courts (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Pee Wee Hockey (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Personnel (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Polo (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Retired, Fees for (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Security (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Soccer/Lacrosse Stadium (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Squash (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Summer Camp Program (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Summer Trimester (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Swimming (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Swimming Coach (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Taxable Properties (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - HEW Legislation (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Tennis (Dixon) (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Tennis (Dixon) (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Tennis Coach (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Tennis (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Tennis (Lyn) (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - TIAA/CREF (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Title IX (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Track (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Training Table (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Users Committee (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Women's Coaches (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Women's Sports (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Wrestling (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Y Society of Yale (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Yale Bowl (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Yale Advisory Committee - Minutes (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Yale Golf Course Advisory Committee (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Yale Golf Course for Charity (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Yale Golf Course Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Yale Golf Course Clubhouse (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Yale Golf Course Director (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Yale Golf Club Gifts (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Yale Golf Course Steering Committee
    - 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Salaries (Box 6, Folder 82)
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2050.